Guide to the Hanover Royal Music Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Music and Books About Music, 1714-1951; Series I; 13.33; (615 boxes)
  - Körner, Gotthilf Wilhelm
    - Music. Print, typeset, undated (Box 95, Folder 459)
  - Kotschoubey, Princess E. B.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 95, Folder 460)
  - Kövesdy, Stefan
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 96, Folder 461)
  - Kozeluch, Leopold, 1747-1818
    - [Sonatas, piano trio]. Trois Sonates Pour le Clavecin ou le Forte Piano avec Violon et Violoncelle.... Op. 21. Parts (pf, vn vc). Print (London: Longman and Broderip), undated (Box 96, Folder 462)
    - [Sonatas, piano trio]. Trois Sonates Pour le Clavecin ou le Piano-Forte avec Accompagnement de Violon et Violoncelle.... Op. 23. Parts (pf, vn vc). Print (Paris: Boyer), undated (Box 96, Folder 463)
    - [Sonatas, piano trio]. Trois Sonates pour le Clavecin ou le Forte-Piano.... Op. 27. Parts (pf, vn vc). Print (Paris: Boyer), undated (Box 96, Folder 464)
    - [Sonatas, piano trio]. Three Sonatas, for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord With Accompaniments for the Violin and Violoncello.... Op. 27. Parts (pf, vn vc). Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 97, Folder 465)
    - [Sonatas, piano trio]. Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord With Accompaniments for the Violin and Violoncello.... Op. 28. Part (pf). Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 97, Folder 466)
    - [Sonata, piano trio]. A Selected Sonata for the Piano Forte...with Accompaniments for a Violin & Bass.... Parts (pf, vn). Print (London: Napier), undated (Box 97, Folder 467)
  - Krall, Johann
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 97, Folder 468)
  - Kretzschmer, A. (Andreas), 1775-1839
    - Deutsche Volkslieder. Volumes 1-2. Print (Berlin: Vereins-Buchhandlung), 1840 (Box 605-606)
  - Krollmann, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 607)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 608)
  - Krüger, Fr.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 97, Folder 469)
  - Krüger, Th.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 97, Folder 470)
  - Kücken, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1810-1882
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 98, Folder 471-472)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 98, Folder 473)
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 609-611)
  - Kühmstedt, Friedrich, 1809-1858
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 98, Folder 474)
  - Kühner, W.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 98, Folder 475)
  - Kulenkamp
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 98, Folder 476)
  - Kündig, Felix
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 98, Folder 477)
  - Kurpinski, Karol, 1785-1857
    - [Polonaise, orchestra]. Polonoise, a Grand Orchestre, sur les Themes de Rule Britania et God Save the King.... Score. Manuscript, 1819 October (Box 98, Folder 478)
  - Kutzing, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1888? (Box 612-613)
      Laid in: autograph letter, signed, from the composer
  - Labitzky, Joseph, 1802-1881
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 99, Folder 479-480)
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 614)
  - Lammers, Julius
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 99, Folder 481)
  - Lang, August
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 99, Folder 482)
  - Lang, Josephine, 1815-1880
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 99, Folder 483)
  - Lange, Otto Heinrich
    - Music. Manuscript, 1859? (Box 615)
  - Lannoy de Clervaux, Countess Clementine
    - Trois Sonates Pour le Piano-Forte avec accompagnement d'un Violon obligé et Violoncelle.... Op. 1. Parts (pf, fl). Manuscript, undated (Box 99, Folder 484)
  - Lasso, Orlando di, 1532-1594
    - Music. Print, 1833, undated (Box 100, Folder 485-488)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 616)
  - Latour, T.
    - A New Overture for the Piano Forte, In which is Introduced the favourite Air of She Lives in the Valley Below...No.9.... Print (London: Bland & Wellers), undated (Box 101, Folder 489)
  - Lauer, Baron von
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 617)
  - Le Camus, J. P.
    - The Muse of grief At the tomb of George the Fourth...For one, two, or three Voices...With an Accompaniment for the Piano-Forte or Harp.... Score. Print (London: J. B. Cramer), undated; (3 copies) (Box 101, Folder 490)
  - Le Sueur, Le Chr.
    - The Battle of Lincelles: A Favorite Sonata for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an accompaniment for the violin.... Score. Print (London: A. Bland & Weller's), undated (Box 101, Folder 491)
      Dedication to Prince Adolphus
  - Lee, Bernard
    - No. 6, Aurora che Sorgerai and Rossini's Grand March.... Score and part (fl). Print (London: Mayhew & Co.), undated (Box 101, Folder 492)
  - Leitermayer, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 618)
  - Leitmann, H. E. C.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 619)
  - Leitmann, Heinrich
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 620)
  - Lemoine, H.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 101, Folder 493)
  - Lenz, Fritz
    - Königlich Hannoversche Hof-Jagd-Signale. Print (Hamburg: Dreissig), 1897 (Box 101, Folder 494)
  - Lenz, L.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 101, Folder 495)
  - Léonard, Hubert, 1819-1890
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 101, Folder 496)
  - Liebe, Henry
    - Two Cotillions arranged for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 102, Folder 497)
    - Six Military Divertimentos for a full Band.... Parts (2 fl, 6 cl (5 parts), 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt). Print (London: for the author, by Preston), undated (Box 102, Folder 498)
  - Limnander
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 102, Folder 499)
  - Lindemann, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1847? (Box 102, Folder 500)
  - Lindner, August, 1820-1878
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 102, Folder 501)
  - Lindpaintner, Peter Joseph von, 1791-1856
    - Danina oder Joko der Brasilianische Affe.... Ballet. Arranged for piano by Ludwig Schunke. Print (Mannheim: Heckel), 1830? (Box 103, Folder 502)
  - Linwood, Mary, 1755-1845
    - David's First Victory, A Sacred Oratorio.... Vocal score. Print (London: author), undated; (2 copies) (Box 621-622)
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 623)
  - Logier, Johann Bernhard, d. 1846
    - The Last Battle: A Grand Charactaristic Sinfonie For a full Military Band.... Parts (2 fl (1 part), 5 cl (4 parts), 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part), 2 trbn (1 part), timp). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 103, Folder 503-504)
      With additional parts in an unidentified 20th century hand
  - Luther, John Christian
    - A Set of Easy Familiar Introductory Lessons Calculated for the Use of Young Performers on the Harpsichord or Piano Forte... Print (London: author), undated (Box 103, Folder 505)
  - Maberly, Mrs.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 624)
  - Maere, Auguste de
    - Music. Manuscript and print, lithograph, undated (Box 625)
  - Mahr, Anton
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 103, Folder 506)
  - Mallick, J. G.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 103, Folder 507)
  - Mammatt, Edward
    - Six vocal Services...for Four Voices. Score. Print (London: Hehl), undated; (2 copies) (Box 626)
  - Mannstein, H. F. (Heinrich Ferdinand)
    - Geschichte, Geist und Ausübung des Gesanges von Gregor dem Grossen bis auf unsere Zeit.... Print (Leipzig: B. G. Teubner), 1845 (Box 627)
  - Marlay, Mrs.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 103, Folder 508)
  - Marschner, Heinrich, 1795-1861
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 628)
      Accompanied by correspondence and music, 1950-1953 and undated
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 104, Folder 509-510)
  - Marshall, William, 1749-1833
    - Marshall's Scottish Airs, Melodies, Strathspeys, Reels, &c..... For piano, harp, violin, and violoncello. Part (pf). Print (Edinburgh: author), undated (Box 104, Folder 511)
  - Martín y Soler, Vicente, 1754-1806
    - [Cosa rara. Consola le pene mia vita]. Consola Le Pene...in the opera of La Cosa Rara... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1789 (Box 104, Folder 512)
    - [Cosa rara. Excerpt]. Terzetto.... Vocal score. Manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 513)
      First line: Oh Dio, oh Dio...
      Inscribed: H.R.H. the duke of Cumberlands
    - [Cosa rara. Excerpt]. Villanelle che volgete...in the Opera of La Cosa Rara.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 104, Folder 514)
    - [Più bianca di giglio]. Cavatina.... Score. Manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 515)
    - [Scuola dei maritati. Overture]. Ouverture und Gesänge aus der Oper die gebessserte Eigensinnige.... Vocal score. Print (N. Simrock: Bonn), undated (Box 105, Folder 516)
    - [Scuola dei maritati]. Douze Nouvelles Suites d'harmonie à 8 Parties de l'opera de la Cappriciosa Corretta...Suivies de Marches et pas Redoubles par J. Gebauer...11e Livraison. Suite 118. Arranged by J. Stumpf. Parts (2 fl, 4 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn, 2 spt, 5 hn, 2 tpt). Print (Paris: Sieber), undated (Box 105, Folder 517)
      Some parts in manuscript
      No music by Gebauer present.
  - Martini, Johann Paul Aegidius, 1741-1816
    - [Nocturnes]. Sei Notturni Per L'Arpa o Cembalo, con due Violini e Violoncello.... Op. 4. Racolta dell'harmonia Collettione Vigesima Sexta. Part (pf). Print (Paris: au Bureau d'Abonnement musical), undated (Box 105, Folder 518)
    - Prière pour le Roi... For chorus and orchestra. Score. Print (London: by De Curt), 1793 (Box 105, Folder 519)
      Text by De Curt
      Signed by De Curt, and inscribed to Princess Augusta
  - Mattheson, Johann, 1681-1764
    - Exemplarische Organisten-Probe Im Artikel vom General-Bass.... Print (Hamburg: Im Schiller- und Kissnerischen Buch-Laden), 1719 (Box 629)
      Frontispiece portrait and half-title in facsimile
      Inscribed: J. Koehler Breslau...1808
  - Mayr, Giovanni Simone, 1763-1845
    - Twelve Venetian Ballads... Score. Print (London: Lavenu), 1797 (Box 105, Folder 520)
      Signed: Cath. Salvini
  - Mayrhofer, Steffen
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 630)
  - Mazzinghi, Joseph, 1765-1844
    - Handel's Overtures Arranged for the Piano-Forte, with an Accompaniment Ad Libitum for a Flute or Violin.... Parts (pf, fl/vn). Print (London: Goulding, Phipps & D'Almaine), undated (Box 105, Folder 521)
    - [Sonatas]. Three Sonatas for the Harp or Piano Forte and an Accompanyment for a Flute or Violin, And Two French Horns, Ad Libitum.... Op. 30. Parts (pf, fl/vn, 2 hn (1 part)). Print (London: Goulding), undated (Box 106, Folder 522)
    - Ramah Droog, or, Wine does Wonders.... Opera. Vocal score. Print (London: Goulding Phipps & D'Almaine), undated (Box 631)
      Signed by Princess Amelia, and inscribed to Amelia by Princess Augusta
  - Meder, C. G.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1838?, 1856 (Box 106, Folder 523)
  - Méhul, Etienne Nicolas, 1763-1817
    - [Héléna]. Helene: Oper in drey Akten.... Vocal score, by G. B. (Gottlob Benedikt) Bierey. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated (Box 106, Folder 524)
    - [Sonatas, piano]. Three Sonatas for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: Bland & Wellers), undated (Box 106, Folder 525)
  - Meluzzi, Salvatore, 1813-1897
    - Music. Print, 1850? (Box 106, Folder 526)
      Inscribed by the composer to [Arnold?] Wehner, 1862
  - Mencke, J. C.
    - His Majesty King William the 4th's March, Compos'd and arangd with Flute, Violin & Violincelle accompangement ad libitum.... Part (pf). Manuscript, undated (Box 106, Folder 527)
      Possibly in the hand of a member of the royal family
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847
    - [Lieder ohne Worte]. Print (Bonn: Simrock), undated (Box 632)
      Signed by Arnold Wehner
    - [95. Psalm]. Der LXXXXVste Psalm.... Score. Print (Leipzig: Kistner), undated (Box 106, Folder 528)
    - [95. Psalm]. Der LXXXXVste Psalm.... Vocal score. Print (Leipzig: Kistner), undated (Box 107, Folder 529)
      With one page of alternate manuscript music
    - [Psalms]. Print, undated (Box 107, Folder 530-531)
    - [Psalms]. Print, undated (Box 633)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 107-109, Folder 532-537)
  - Menge, Georg
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 109, Folder 538)
  - Menge, Georg Friedrich
    - Music. Print, typeset, undated (Box 634)
  - Mengozzi, Bernardo, 1758-1800
    - [Gli schiavi per amore]. Donne, Donne chi vi crede...in the Opera of Gli Schiavi per Amore.... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1787 (Box 109, Folder 539)
  - Methfessel, Albert Gottlieb, 1785-1869
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 109, Folder 540)
  - Mettenleiter, Dominicus, 1822-1868
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 109, Folder 541)
  - Mettenleiter
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 635)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 109, Folder 542)
  - Miles, Thomas, ca. 1780-ca. 1852
    - Six Trios for Two Trebles and a Bass.... Score. Print (London: for the author by Goulding), undated (Box 109, Folder 543)
  - Miller, Edward, 1735-1807
    - The Psalms of David for the Use of Parish Churches.... Print (London: W. Miller), 1790? (Box 636)
  - Moeser, Carl
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 110, Folder 544)
  - Molck, Heinrich
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 110, Folder 545)
    - Music. Manuscript and print, 1866, undated (Box 637)
      With autograph letter, signed, from the composer to Ernst August (1845-1923), as Crown Prince of Hanover
  - Molck, J. H. C.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 638)
  - Mombelli, Domenico, 1751-1835
    - Six Italian arietts.... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1790 (Box 110, Folder 546)
  - Montalembert, Marquise de
    - Six Sonatas for the Harpsichord.... Print (London: no publisher), 1794 April (Box 110, Folder 547)
  - Moody, Marie
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 110, Folder 548)
  - Mortellari, Antonio
    - Twelve Arietts...for the Piano Forte or Harp.... Print (London: Henry Holland), 1791? (Box 639)
      Date from binding
  - Moscheles, Ignaz, 1794-1870
    - The Tyrolese Melodies.... For voices and piano. Score. Print (London: Willis), 1827? (Box 640)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
    See also: Reutter, Georg, 1708-1772
    - La Clemenza di Tito.... Vocal score. Second edition. Print (Hamburg: Böhme), undated (Box 641)
    - [Divertimenti, K. 247, F major]. No. 2, Sextour. Parts (2nd vn, va, b, 2 hn). Print (no publisher), undated (Box 110, Folder 549)
    - [Divertimenti, K. 287, B-flat major]. Mozart Sextour No. 3. Parts (2 vn, va, b, 2 hn). Print (no publisher), undated (Box 111, Folder 550)
    - [Don Giovanni]. Don Juan, oder Der steinerne Gast.... Vocal score. Arranged by Friedrich Schneider. Print, typeset (Leipzig: Karl Tauchnitz), undated (Box 642)
    - [Don Giovanni. Là ci darem la mano]. La ci darem la mano: A Favourite Duett in the Opera Il Don Giovanni.... Vocal score. Print (London: Birchall), circa 1800 (Box 111, Folder 551)
    - [Finta giardiniera]. Auswahl der vorzüglichsten Arien und Gesänge...Ites-IItes Heft. Early edition. Print (Leipzig: in Commission bey Breitkopf und Härtel), circa 1797 (Box 111, Folder 552)
    - [Idomeneo. Overture]. The Overture to Idomeneo for a Grand Orchestra.... Parts (2 fl (1 part), 2 ob (1 part), 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn (1 part), trp, timp, 2 vn, va, b). Print (London: Monzani & Hill), circa 1815 (Box 111, Folder 553)
    - [Nozze di Figaro. Overture]. Ouverture à grand orchestre de l'opéra: Le nozze di Figaro.... Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp, 2 vn, va, b and vc (1 part)). Print (Offenbach: Jean André), undated (Box 111, Folder 554)
    - [Quintet, violins, violas, violoncello, K. 516, G minor]. Grand Quintetto.... Parts (2nd vn, 2 va, vc). Print (London: Broderip & Wilkinson), undated (Box 111, Folder 555)
    - [Quintet, violins, violas, violoncello, K. 593, D major]. Grand Quintetto.... Parts (2nd vn, va, vc). Print (London: Broderip & Wilkinson), undated (Box 112, Folder 556)
    - [Schauspieldirektor. Overture]. Ouverture à grand orchestre de l'opera der Schauspieldirector.... Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn (1 part, 2 copies), 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part), timp, 2 vn, va, vc and b (1 part)). Print (Offenbach: J. André), 1802 (Box 112, Folder 557)
    - [Symphony, K. 297, D major]. Sinfonie en Harmonie.... No. 1. Arranged by Karl Andreas Goepfert. Parts (2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn and spt (2 parts), 2 hn, tpt). Print (Bonn: N. Simrock), undated (Box 112, Folder 558)
    - [Trio, piano, strings, K. 564, G major]. Trio Per il Clavicembalo o Forte Piano con l'accompagnamento d'un Violino e Violoncello.... Part (kbd). Print (Vienna: Artaria), 1790 (Box 112, Folder 559)
      First Viennese edition
    - [Variations, piano]. Oeuvres de Mozart. Cahier II. Contenant Douze Thémes variés pour le Pianoforte.... Print, typeset (Leipzig: Au Magasin de Musique de Breitkopf & Härtel), 1798 (Box 643)
    - [Variations, piano]. Air with Variations for the Harpsichord or Piano Forte.... No. 7, Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1787 (Box 112, Folder 560)
  - Mueller von Asow, E. H. (Erich Hermann), 1892-1964
    - Deutsches Musiker-Lexikon. Print (Dresden: W. Limpert), 1929 (Box 644)
  - Mugnie, J.
    - God save the King, with eight variations including a grand march with a violin or flute and violoncello.... Parts (kbd, fl or vn, b). Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 112, Folder 561)
  - Müller, C. F.
    - Rule Britannia Arrangirt für grosse Cavalleriemusik.... Parts (4 hn, 3 tpt, 4 trbn, 2 b). Manuscript, undated (Box 112, Folder 562)
    - Douze Marches originales pour grande Musique Militaire.... Op. 55. Parts (fl, 2 ob, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 6 hn, 2 tpt, 3 trbn, 2 drum). Print, lithograph (no publisher), undated; (2 copies) (Box 645)
      One copy has two 2nd oboe parts, and no 1st oboe part
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 646)
  - Müller, C. G.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 647)
  - Müller, Carl
    - Rundgesang auf die frohe Zurückkunft des...herzogs...Carl Wilhelm Ferdinand.... Score. Print, typeset (Brunswick: Kircher), 1794 (Box 113, Folder 563)
  - Müller, Matheus
    - Ode auf Sir Warrens Sieg.... Score. Print, typescript (no publisher), 1798 (Box 113, Folder 564)
      With parts (SATB, 2 fl, ob, 2 cl, 2 bn, contrabn, 2 hn, tpt, timp)
  - Müller, Wenzel, 1759-1835
    - [Fagottist]. Die Zauberzitter.... Vocal score. Print (Dresden: im Hilscherschen Musik-Verlage), undated (Box 648)
      Overture and numbers 2-27; some numbers missing
    - [Das Neusonntagskind]. Das neue Sonntagskind oder der Geisterseher.... Vocal score. Print (Dresden: im Hilscherschen Music Verlage), undated (Box 649)
      Numbers 18, 19, 29-36, 44-49
  - Mund, C. W.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 113, Folder 565)
  - Munro Browne, C.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 113, Folder 566)
  - Mussini, Natale
    - Six Ariettes.... Score. Print (Zerbst: C. C. Menzel), undated (Box 113, Folder 567)
  - Napier, William, 1740?-1812
    - Napier's Selection of Dances & Strathspeys, with new and appropriate basses.... For piano or harp. Print (London: W. Napier), circa 1795 (Box 113, Folder 568)
  - Negri, Benedetto, 1784-1854
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 113, Folder 569)
  - Neithardt, A. (August), 1793-1861
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 114-115, Folder 570-577)
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 650-653)
  - Nigg, Wilhelm
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 654)
  - Norton, Robert F.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 116, Folder 578)
  - Oertzen, C. L. v.
    - Krönungs-Marscm [sic] zu Schiller's Jungfrau von Orleans für das grosse Orchester... Arranged for piano, 4 hands. Parts on facing pages. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), undated (Box 116, Folder 579)
      Blind stamp of Princess Augusta
    - [Der Rune letzter Spruch. Overture]. Ouverture zu dem Festspiel Der Rune letzter Spruch von Barth...aufgeführt...am 26.ten April 1835.... Arranged for piano. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger) (Box 116, Folder 580)
    - Vandalia, Mecklenburgisches Volkslied von Bahrdt.... Score. Print (Neustrelitz: Dümmler), undated (Box 116, Folder 581)
  - Oesterley, Ferdinand
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 655)
  - Ommeren, Ferdinand van
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 116, Folder 582)
  - Onslow, Georges, 1784-1853
    - An Air, for the Piano Forte, the Variations Composed for and Dedicated (by Permission) to Her Royal Highness The Princess Augusta.... Op. 28. Print (London: J. Boosey & Co.), undated (Box 116, Folder 583)
  - Ortigue, Joseph d', 1802-1866
    - Dictionnaire liturgique, historique et théorique de plain-chant et de musique d'église. Print (Paris: Potier), 1854 (Box 656)
  - Oswald, James, 1710-1769
    - [Fortunatus]. The Comic Tunes in Fortunatus.... For harpsichord and violin, flute, or oboe. Score. Print (London: Oswald), undated (Box 116, Folder 584)
    - [The Genii]. The Comic Tunes in the Genii.... For harpsichord and violin, flute, or oboe. Score. Print (London: Oswald), undated (Box 116, Folder 585)
  - Page, John, ca. 1760-1812
    - Harmonia Sacra, A Collection of Anthems in Score.... Volumes 1-3. Score. Print (London: for the editor), 1800 (Box 657-659)
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816
    - [Il barbiere di Siviglia. Excerpt]. Ah Chi Sa, The Favorite Trio in the Comic Opera Il Barbier di Siviglia.... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1789 (Box 116, Folder 586)
    - [Elfrida. Excerpt]. Abbracciami o Sposo, The Favorite Duett...in the Opera of Elfrida.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), circa 1800 (Box 116, Folder 587)
    - [Elfrida. Excerpt]. Credi la mia ferita, The favorite Duett...in Elfrida.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), 1798; (2 copies) (Box 116, Folder 588)
    - [Molinara. Excerpt]. Nel cor più non mi sento, The celebrated Duetto...in the Opera of La Molinarella.... Score. Print (London: for the proprietors), undated (Box 117, Folder 589)
    - [Nina. Excerpt]. O Momento Fortunato The Favorite Duett...in the Opera of Nina.... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated; (2 copies) (Box 117, Folder 590)
    - [I zingari in fiera. Excerpt]. Duetto Sung by Sigra Storace & Sigr Morelli in...I Zingari in Fiera.... Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 117, Folder 591)
    - [I zingari in fiera. Excerpt]. Irco dell' Erebo...in the Favorite Opera of I Zingari in Fiera.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 117, Folder 592)
  - Palestrina, Giovanni Pierluigi da, 1525?-1594
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 117, Folder 593)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 660-663)
  - Pannenberg, Friedrich Wilhelm
    - Zwölf Sleiver und zwey Quadrille.... Parts (2 fl, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn, 2 vn, b). Print, typeset (Rinteln: Bösendahl), 1792 (Box 117, Folder 594)
  - Panofka, Heinrich, 1807-1887
    - Music. Print, 1854 (Box 664)
  - Panormo, F. C. (Ferdinand Charles)
    - Massena's Retreat, A Grand March, And Quick Step.... For keyboard. Print (London: G. Walker), undated (Box 117, Folder 595)
    - Trumpet Rondo, For the Piano Forte.... Print (London: for the author, by G. Walker), undated (Box 117, Folder 596)
  - Panormo, Francis, 1764-1844
    - Le Char de Cythérée, A Sonata for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: Bland & Wellers), undated (Box 117, Folder 597)
    - Cuidad Rodrigo, A Military Divertimento composed for the Piano-forte.... Print (London: G. Walker), undated (Box 118, Folder 598)
    - Six Favourite Airs, with Variations for the Piano Forte.... Op. 17. Print (London: author), undated (Box 118, Folder 599)
    - Six favourite airs with variations for the harp or piano-forte.... Print (no publisher), undated (Box 118, Folder 600)
      Book-seller's label: Music Warehouse
    - Un Joli Rien Pour le Piano Forte.... Print (London: Joseph Kemp), 1808 (Box 118, Folder 601)
    - Les Plaisirs de Margate, A Favorite Divertimento for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: L. Lavenu), undated (Box 118, Folder 602)
  - Panseron, Auguste-Mathieu, 1795-1859
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 118, Folder 603)
  - Papendiek, Christopher, 1755-1826
    - Trio for the Harpsichord or piano Forte with an Accompaniment for a Flauto & Violoncello Obligato... Parts (kbd, fl, vc). Manuscript, undated (Box 118, Folder 604)
  - Pappertiz, Robert